太空堡垒卡拉狄加 【前情提要】
STARBUCK: Previously on Battlestar Galactica.
何不帮自己一个忙?
Why don't you do yourself a favor?
交出你的书 《我的成与败》
Hand over your book. My Triumphs, My Mistakes,
盖尤斯・波塔尔著
by Gaius Baltar.
人们都在看这本书  现在你后悔了
The people are reading it, and now you're sorry.
波塔尔会受到审判
Baltar will get his trial.
而你面临的将是一场风暴
And this is what you'll get, a hurricane.
派别冲突
You'll have sectarian violence.
暗杀企图
You will have assassination attempts.
还有你从没见过的大规模骚乱
You will have civil unrest on a scale we've never seen.
总统想尽快审判波塔尔
The President wants to take the fast track on Baltar's trial.
她想找个人主管准备工作
She's looking for someone to take charge of the preliminaries,
完善相关法律体系 她想让我选派你
help cobble together the legal framework. She wants me to assign you.
这是我爷爷写的法律书   你爸爸给你的
APOLLO: These are my grandfather's law books. DUALLA: It's from your father.
星芭  我是阿波罗  我在雷达上找不到你
Starbuck, Apollo. I've lost you on dradis.
不 不
No! No!
李
ADAMA: Lee.
我们会立即派出搜救队 会找到她的
We're sending in the search and rescue birds right now. We'll find her.
不  爸  没用了  她的战机已经变成碎片了
No, Dad, it's no use. Her ship is in pieces.
我们失去她了
We lost her.
这里有舰队每位船长的名字
ROSLIN: Here's every Captain from every ship in the fleet.
伊莱亚斯・密克船长  吉迪恩
"Captain Elias Meeker, Gideon. "
最后一名法官是...
And the last name for the tribunal is...
阿...
Goodness...
我看到相似之处了
Yeah. Yeah, I see the resemblance.
再来个朝上的
SAM: One more for heads!
看着
Watch.
朝上的  看到了吗?  都四次了
Heads! You see that? Four in a row.
真他妈是奇迹  看着...再来一次
It's a frakking miracle. Watch this one more time.
肯定还是朝上的 看着
It's gonna be heads. Watch.
朝上!  每次都是  你们看见到吗?  朝上的
Heads. Every time. You see it? It's heads.
嘿  你干吗不从那儿下来?      我在这儿很好
Hey, why don't you come down from there? I'm just fine right here, man.
少校
Major?
什么事?
Yeah?
朝上!
Heads!
看到了吗?  幸运女神总是眷顾我
You see that? My girl's too lucky to check out.
嘿  山姆      李
Hey, Sam.  Lee.
阿波罗  就站在那  兄弟
Apollo. You stay there, buddy.
你喝高了
Well, you're flying.
先下来睡个觉吧 来
Let's just get down and get some sleep, come on.
我很好  我要坐下来
I'm just, I'm fine. I'm just gonna sit down.
噢
Ow.
你还好吧?
You all right?
她不该…  别这样
She wasn't... It wasn't... Come on.
不  我要走了
No. I gotta go.
妈的
Oh, frak!
他妈的 他还好吗?
Frak. Is he okay?
啊  我想我摔倒了
I think I fell.
山姆  山姆
Sam, Sam.
她还活着  对吗?
She's still alive, right?
不  她死了  山姆  死了  我知道
She's gone, Sam. She's gone. I know.
是
Yeah.
着陆信号官  我是蝮蛇6号  请求长距着陆
HOTDOG: LSO, Viper Six. Request long approach.
蝮蛇6号  我是着陆信号官  准许着陆
KELLY: Viper Six, LSO. Viper approved.
没想到我会怀念星芭的伶牙俐齿
Never thought I'd miss all of Starbuck's yakking.
是啊  长官
Yes, sir.
恭喜了
Your Honor.
你没听到
You haven't heard?
你去哪了? 他们刚刚公布  你中奖了
Where you been? They just announced it. You won the lottery.
波塔尔五分之一的小贱命就掌握在你手里了
You now own exactly one-fifth of Baltar's skinny ass.
法官席上审判波塔尔的五名船长当中 有你一个
You're one of five Captains picked to serve on the judge's tribunal.
嗯
Hmm.
他来了
Here he comes.
妈的
Frak.
运送波塔尔的律师
It's a waste of my time
在和风号之间飞来飞去是浪费时间和精力
and energy flying Baltar's lawyer back and forth from Zephyr.
跟我说说具体的  知道最糟糕的是什么吗?
Yeah, tell me about it. Wanna know what the worst part is?
他就坐在我后面 还凑上来想跟我说悄悄话
He sits back there and tries to whisper into my ear when he talks.
我还戴着头盔呢  不好意思
I've got a helmet. Sorry.
休斯先生
Mr. Hughes.
他要是再在我的猛禽号里脱鞋子 我也许会杀了他
He takes his shoes off in my Raptor again, I might have to kill him.
当事人 谁都知道他有罪 他把我们的位置告诉了赛昂人
Client. Everybody knows he's guilty. He gave the Cylons our location.
还审那狗娘养的干吗?
Why even give the son of a bitch a trial?
因为他有权利
Because he's entitled.
即使是他也有  这就叫公正
Even him. It's called justice.
是啊  权利!
Yeah, right.
依我看  波塔尔死了
To see Baltar dead
星芭活着  那才叫公正呢
and Starbuck alive. That would be justice.
根本没有公正 看他喝的那样…
There's no justice. As drunk as he was...
赛道
SKULLS: Racetrack!
赛道你还好吧?  赛道
CALLY: Racetrack, are you okay? Racetrack!
救护员!
CALLY: Medic!
好了  好了  我接到他了  我接到他了 好
Yeah, yeah. I got him, I got him. Okay, okay.
你还好吗
You okay?
总统女士  总统女士
Madam President! Madam President!
你打算如何替换波塔尔的辩护律师呢?
How do you intend to replace Gaius Baltar's defense attorney?
也用抽签的方式吗?
Will that be done by lottery as well?
我们有把握尽快找到顶替人选
We're confident we'll replace him shortly.
有很多候选人  我们正按名单筛选  下一个
There's a number of candidates, we're working our way down the list. Next.
总统女士  总统女士
Madam President, Madam President. Karen.
考虑到这次爆炸显然这不是意外
Taken in the context of this explosion, which obviously was no accident,
您真的为认进行为这次审判
do you really think that it's in the best interest of the fleet
符合舰队的最佳利益吗?
to proceed with this trial?
政府绝不会接受恐怖主义
This administration will never bow to terrorism.
总统女士  总统女士
Madam President! Madam President!
等等  让我对大家说说这件事
ROSLIN: Wait. You know, let me say something here, to all of you.
让我说清楚了  好吗?
Let me get this clear, all right?
只要我还是总统
As long as I am President,
政府就不会允许任何恐怖主义
this administration will not allow terrorism
破坏我们的法律体制
to alter the framework of our legal system.
我们将进行严正审判
We will proceed with the trial.
谢谢大家
Rigorously. Thank you. All of you.
还有一个问题  请等等
One more question?
西洛  我要你带蓝队到7号区建立雷达哨所
Helo, I need you to set up a dradis picket with Blue Squadron in Sector 7.
呃  对不起  长官  你的意思是到9号地区吗?
Excuse me, sir. You mean Sector 9, right?
呃…
Uh...
对 对 9号 上次我们扫描过8号地区了
Right. Right, 9. Um, yeah, we scrubbed 8 on the last picket.
那里没什么动静  自然是到下一个区了
It's been so quiet, one pick just flows into the next.
好吧
Okay.
定位81  22度
81 carom, 22 degrees.
保持警惕 一旦发现赛昂人 立马撤退
Keep your ears open. Any Cylon contact, just shut down, bug out.
红队
Red Squadron.
你们跟着我进行首次空中巡逻
You'll be riding first CAP with me.
并且  现在开始  两队轮班
And from here on, double shifts.
雅典娜  我要你专门负责往返飞行
Athena, I'm gonna need you exclusively on shuttle runs.
别忘了检查你们的后座底下
Well, don't forget to check under your back seat.
嘿  算你运气好  星芭
Hey, hey, you got lucky, Starbuck.
如果我是你  我会考虑去买...
If I were you, I would seriously consider buying a low...
是赛道 对不起
Racetrack, I'm sorry.
解散  解散
Dismissed. Dismissed.
知道你并不害怕  很是让人鼓舞
Well, it's so comforting to know that you're not afraid.
你并不害怕为这世上最被痛恨的家伙辩护
You're not afraid to represent the most hated man alive.
问题是  你是为了什么呢?
The question is why?
为了名气  荣誉
For the fame, the glory.
你曾在卡布里卡的公诉机关工作过
You worked in the Public Litigation Office on Caprica.
你觉得你能胜任这样级别的案子吗?
You think you have the qualifications to handle a case of this magnitude?
我天生就是干这个的
I was born for this.
事实上我有动力
That, and the fact that I have a pulse.
兰斯是我妻子的
Lance belonged to my wife.
别担心 "他"不会像"她"那样乱抓乱咬
Don't worry. He doesn't scratch or bite like she did.
如果能使你感到安慰的话 那我就小小地鄙视"他"一下
If it's of any comfort, I despise him as much as you do,
就像你不得不雇用我
having to hire me.
那么  到点子上了
So, there it is.
我们可以开始了吗?
Shall we get started?
我要你负责那个新律师的安全问题
I'm gonna need you to handle the security detail on the new attorney.
我
Me.
说白了  你是把我停飞了
So, that's it? You're grounding me.
你是我唯一可以相信的人
You're the only one I can trust.
你就直说吧
You know, just say it.
你扯我后腿
You're pulling me.
保证拉姆金的生命安全是一项很重要的任务
Keeping Lampkin alive is an important job.
我需要你的帮助
I need your help.
爸爸  我很好
Dad, I'm fine.
不  你不好
No, you're not.
为什么?
Why?
因为我不好
Because I'm not.
是吗?  那也许你该休息一下
Yeah? Well, then, maybe you should take a rest.
西洛将暂时担任空军飞行队长
Helo will be stepping in as CAG.
我要你在船上
I want you on this ship.
不是那上面 直到你能够把这事搞定
Not up there. Not until you can work this out.
好啊
Right.
我理解
I understand.
搞定它
Work it out.
行啊
Okay.
我将负责你的安全 你想把包放在哪里?
I'll be handling security for you. Where do you want your bags?
你会有两个卫兵在门外站岗
You'll have two Marines stationed outside the door.
卡西迪小姐  控方律师  她就在走廊那一边
Ms. Cassidy, the Prosecuting Attorney, she's just down the hall.
有个厕所
There's a head.
浴室在那边  不好意思  男女混用的
Showers are that way. Sorry, co-ed.
还有其他的事吗?
Now, if there's anything else.
我要见我的当事人
I'd like to see my client.
现在?
Now?
飞行员?      是的
Pilot. Yeah.
王牌飞行员
King of the pilots.
如果你愿意的话
We could stand around
我们就在这讨论一下是什么把你和我拴在一块儿了
here and discuss why you got stuck with me, if you want.
我带你去他的牢房   不 不去那里
I'll take you to his cell. No, no. Not there.
可能船上一半的人都会去偷听
Half the ship's probably listening in.
好吧  无论如何  我们有审讯室
Fine, whatever. We have an interrogation room.
审讯室会让我怯场
Interrogation rooms give me stage fright.
我不能带他来这里
I can't bring him here.
我觉得你的房间不错
I was thinking your quarters.
什么?
What?
是的  在布满窃听线路以前
Yeah, before it gets wired for sound,
像这里也许就有
like this place probably is.
有什么问题吗?  你没叠被子?
What's the problem? You forgot to make your bed?
听着  我不在乎你在哪里见他  我只是不能让你一个人呆着
Look, I don't care where you see him. I just can't leave you alone.
少校
Major.
是少校  对吗?
It is Major, isn't it?
我有权
I have the right
与我的当事人私下交谈
to consult with my client in private,
在没有任何人偷听偷看的情况下
without anybody eavesdropping or looking in.
"小心驶得万年船"   这上面就是这么写的
Whoever cares the most, wins. Says so in there.
所以?
So?
我要见我的当事人  你不在乎的  我赢了
I want to see my client, you don't care, I win.
你知道  你长得很像他
You know, you look like him.
你认识我爷爷?
You knew my grandfather?
恨他入骨
Hated his guts.
我知道的一切都是他教的
He taught me everything I know.
你在这儿干什么呢?
What are you doing here, anyway?
你可以自由地说话
You can speak freely.
他签署了保密协议
He signed confidentiality papers.
听着  这套把戏真可悲
Look, this whole charade's pathetic.
可悲!
Pathetic.
护卫?
Security?
护卫早已在庆祝我另一个律师的无故暴毙了吧
Security is already toasting my other attorney's untimely demise.
那个家伙除了打盹以外做过的唯一的事
About the only thing that bloke ever did, apart from napping, was, you know,
就是偷偷地
manage to
把我的书稿带出去
smuggle out my papers.
纸 你有纸么?
Papers. Do you have any papers?
谢谢
Thank you.
"成见…
The nature
是现代人…
of modern life
的天性"
is obsession.
告诉我
So, tell me.
你真的认为我会得到公正的审判吗?
Do you honestly think that I'm gonna get a fair trial?
我怀疑  就是
Doubtful. Yes.
但现在你也没自救吧?
But you haven't exactly been helping yourself now, have you?
你反对我写这些吗?
You object to my writing.
相反  你接着写吧
On the contrary, keep it coming.
这个新宣言显示了你内在的巨大变化
This new manifesto of yours shows a great change in you.
你这个连载的小手册
This little operating manual of yours,
让他们猜测不断
well, it keeps them all guessing.
好  好
Right. Okay, okay.
卡布里卡6号
Caprica Six.
我很担心她
I'm worried about her.
她是关键
She's the key.
他们能利用她
They can use her
彻底毁了我
to completely destroy me.
我们必须接触到她
I need to get to her.
我们需要知道她的想法
I need to know what she's thinking.
我需要…
And I need to...
我需要和她谈谈
I need... Talk to her.
告诉她
Tell her...
告诉她  我非常爱她
Tell her, I love her very much.
我总是惦记着她
That I'm thinking about her a lot.
我能感觉到  是的
I can sense that, yes.
你需要找出我们共同的立场
We need to find out where we're all, where we're all standing.
"要倾听  先得有声音"
"To listen requires a voice,
"要知道什么  就要先提问"
"for what needs to be known requires us to ask. "
《我的成与败》 盖尤斯・波塔尔著
My Triumphs, My Mistakes, by Gaius Baltar.
不过你说的真是不错
But you say it very well.
那些文稿一到
I've done my reading.
我就读了
Once those papers arrive,
我建议你接着写
I suggest you do yours.
带我去殖民地1号
Fly me to Colonial One.
我?
Me?
是啊  你不是飞行员吗?
Yeah, you're a pilot, aren't you?
你不明白 不是你跳进一架猛禽机就能飞
You don't understand. You can't just jump in a Raptor.
有很多事情需要准备协调
These things have to be coordinated.
你更愿意呆在哪  少校  在这里  ?
Where would you rather be, Major, here?
好像出殡的未亡人?
As the parade float for the bereaved?
你在说些什么呢?
What are you talking about?
每个见到你的 都觉得你的心好像在流血
Everybody looking at you like you're bleeding out of your side.
想见识一下真正的血… 就接着说!
You want to see some real blood? Keep going.
哟  有人露出本性啦
Oh, there is someone home.
听着
Look.
我需要那些文件  你和我一起去  他们可能就会给我
I need those files. You come with me, they might just give them to me.
如果我就这么等着
I wait,
他们就会在我拿到手之前发现波塔尔的企图
they're gonna discover that Baltar's pregnant before I get them.
总之  你的工作是什么?  保护我
What is your job, anyway? To keep me alive?
还是妨碍我?
Or to keep me from doing mine?
抱歉  长官  你该知道情况  你必须留在这里
Sorry, sir. You know your status. You're to remain shipside.
这是上将的命令
Those are the Admiral's orders.
因父之名
Father factor.
拜托了凯利  破例一下  我只是搭乘  不驾驶
Come on, Kelly, give me a break. I'm along for the ride.
别难为我  好吗?  我已经够糟糕的了
Don't do this to me. All right? I'm in enough dung already.
好的
All right.
好的  给小鸟儿拽一把～
All right, let's give the bird a tow.
哇 哇
TYROL: Whoa, whoa!
等一下  开门  开门
Hold up! Open the door, open the door.
他妈的什么东西?  你看见没有?
What the frak was that thing? Did you see that?
什么  我想那是只猫
What? What? I think it was a cat.
那是我的猫   有只该死的猫在这里
LAMPKIN: That's my cat. There's a frakking cat in there.
快出来  少校
Come on out of there, Major.
谁他妈的让猫进来的?
Who the hell let a cat in here?
它在另一边  把它赶这边来
He's on the other side, push him over here.
在那  就在那
There it is. It's over there, it's over there.
在那  在那
There it is, there it is, there it is.
猫咪  不不  过来这里
TYROL: Kitty, kitty. No, no, no, come on. Come here, kitty. Come here.
过来这里
Come here, come here.
炸弹!  有炸弹!  大家出去
Bomb! Bomb! Everybody out!
你到底在那里干什么?
What the hell were you doing out there?
我命令你执行任务
I gave you an order to do a job.
对不起  我是在执行任务
Excuse me. I was doing my job.
是啊  被人牵着鼻子到处跑?
Yeah, being led around by the nose?
那个混蛋拉一下项圈你就跟着跳?
This bastard yanks your chain and you jump?
他想要殖民地1号上的文件
He wanted files from Colonial One.
那是半夜
It was the middle of the night.
你让我当他的护卫的
Well, you assigned me to security.
是啊  那船上有颗炸弹
Yeah, and there was a bomb on that ship.
而你没有发现
And you missed it.
护卫?
"Security. "
我给你的命令够清楚了
I gave you explicit orders.
雅典娜在驾驶
Athena was piloting.
你可能会平白无故地死掉
You could have died, plain and simple.
你是一名战士
You're a soldier.
要活的像个战士 表现的像个战士
Live like one. Start acting like one.
她已经死了两周了 我没意识到时钟还在转
She's been gone two weeks. I didn't realize the clock was running.
不要说了   不  对不起
Stop. No, I'm sorry,
也许我们生来就不同
'cause maybe we're just built differently.
别说了
You stop.
你怎知我有多痛苦!
Don't you dare quantify my loss.
你根本不了解
You have no idea.
你他妈的根本不了解
You have no frakking idea.
那你觉得你受伤更深?
What, you think yours is deeper?
你更悲痛欲绝?
Well... Yours is greater?
还有两周
In two weeks,
就要审判了!
there's going to be a trial,
我要做我该做的事 你也是
and I'm gonna do what I was chosen to do, and so are you.
你他妈给我盯紧了
You build a frakking nest around this man,
好生看着他!
and you protect his ass.
该死的这次玩真的了
Frakker meant business this time.
如果爆了
If that thing had gone off, we'd be picking up
猛禽和人都会被炸得粉碎
Raptor and people parts with tweezers.
我每天都和那些机师打招呼
Every day, I wave jocks out there.
很多人都是我朋友 我喜爱的人
A lot of them are my friends, people I care for and love.
看他们在战斗中死去就够难受的了
It's hard enough watching them die in battle,
还要去给波塔尔的混蛋律师陪葬?    滚他妈的!
but rickshawing Baltar's frakking attorney around? Frak that.
我相信赛昂人是想要我们自相残杀
I believe that the Cylons want us to destroy ourselves,
并且他们正在这样做
and this is how they're doing it.
通过安置炸弹
By planting bombs,
让我们相互猜疑
making us suspicious of each other.
你们知道最可笑的是什么?  等赛昂人追上我们时
You know what's funny, is by the time the Cylons catch up with us,
根本不用打
they won't even have to attack.
只要收拾烂摊子就行了
They'll just clean up the mess we made.
我觉得这里有赛昂人
I think they're here.
我觉得你错了
I think you're wrong.
好吧  我只知道今早我亲了尼奇
Okay, all I know is, I kissed Nicky this morning
这差点就成了吻别
and it could have been the last time.
够了  凯莉
Cally, that's enough.
什么?  我也亲了你!
What? I kissed you, too.
有些人可能没有第二次机会了
Some of us don't get a second chance.
或者第三次...
Or a third.
我去找上将
I'm going to the Admiral.
好了  仔细看看这个屋子
All right, take a good look at this room.
每次你离开  记住它
Every time you leave, memorize it.
如果有任何变化  别乱动
If anything changes, don't touch it.
一本书动了  鞋子放的地方不对
A book moves, shoes in the wrong place,
什么东西闻起来不对头 你就他妈的马上跑出去
something smells different, you get the frak out.
有人敲门  不给开  不要打开门!
Someone knocks, don't answer the door. Don't open the door.
你必须照我说的去做
Look, you have to do what I say.
如果他们想要杀我  他们总能找到办法
If they want to kill me, they'll find a way.
接下来
Now,
我要贿赂谁才能见那个赛昂女人?
who do I have to bribe to see the Cylon woman?
成见是现代人的天性
The nature of one's life is obsession.
该死的  我找不到我的眼镜了  好像它们长了腿似的
Damn, I can't find my glasses. It's like they've got feet.
6号
The Six.
是的  没问题
Yes, okay.
拉姆金马上就能和6号会面  只要会面条件…
Lampkin can interview Six immediately, as long as it's conducted under
和上次检察长的一样就行  好吗?
the same conditions accorded to the Chief Prosecutor. All right?
就是说要在审讯室里
Meaning in the Interrogation Room,
不是你睡的地方
not where you sleep.
那当然  不过既然你被挑选为法官席的一员
Of course. But since you've been selected to serve on the tribunal,
为了公平起见
I'm assuming that you won't
我想你不会出现在这些会面中
be present at those interviews, in the interest of fairness.
少校说的有道理  比尔
Major has a point, Bill.
少校错了
Major's mistaken.
我监督了检察长的会面
I monitored the Chief Prosecutor's interview.
因此  在同样的条件下
Therefore, same conditions apply.
为了公平起见
In the interest of fairness.
拉姆金先生仍然有权获得
Mr. Lampkin is still entitled to
那些在殖民地1号上的文件
those documents that he requested from Colonial One.
是的  没错  我很抱歉
Yes, right. I apologize.
我们还没找到那些文件
We've had trouble locating the files.
下次送给你们好吗?
We'll have them delivered to you on the next run.
不好意思  少校  我们会很快给你   谢谢
I'm sorry, Major. We'll get them to you right away. Thank you.
谢谢
Thank you.
我知道你与我的当事人有段浪漫的关系
LAMPKIN: I understand that you had a romantic relationship with my client.
盖尤斯・波塔尔是个很有才华的人类
Gaius Baltar is a brilliant, gifted human being.
我认识他的那段时间里
In the time I've known him,
他撒谎成性  诡计多端
he's made a sport out of mendacity and deception.
自恋  自私  软弱  虚伪
He was narcissistic, self-centered, feckless and vain.
我本应该杀了他
I'm the one who should have stabbed him.
里面进展的不错
Things are looking up.
爱情...
Love.
超前的进化步伐使赛昂人…
A precocious evolutionary move, fashioning Cylons
能体验到它
to be capable of experiencing it.
我不知道是不是因为战术上的需要才被加入到你们的程序中
I don't know if it was engineered as a tactical imperative,
但这不为了那个胆小鬼  是吗?
but it's not for the faint-hearted, is it?
没错  不是
No, it's not.
也许你能对你们的"机械小兵"好一些
Maybe you should have been nicer to your mechanic.
也许赛昂人的爱情和人类的不一样
Well, perhaps Cylon love is not the same as human love.
也许它被设计的...伤得不那么深
Perhaps it's designed to hurt a little less.
你怎么知道?
How would you know?
我爱过一个女人
I loved a woman.
非常非常美丽的女人
Beautiful, beautiful woman.
但太严肃了
But so serious.
她那凝眉锁眸让多少社会名流为之倾倒
This frowning face trapped in the middle of a daisy.
她走路的样子...
She had a way of walking.
神圣得...
Processional.
好象圣女去就义一般
As if she were on her way to her own execution.
我们在一起生活了十年
We had 10 years.
最后被迫分手
Then it fell apart under its own weight.
这是你想要的结果吗?
Is that what you wanted?
我认为如果我能忘记她 我就能克服一切
I thought if I could get over her, I could get over anything.
我就能忍受
I could endure,
超越 做个男人
conquer, be a man.
经得起任何的伤害
Stand up to any and all kind of punishment.
有好几个月  我独守空床  辗转反侧
I clung to an empty, spinning bed for months.
而那时候
And that?
我才终于意识到我是多么地爱她
That is when I finally realized how much I loved her.
我费尽力气才明白...
If I needed all that strength,
关键是什么
what was the point?
我要和她在一起
I needed to be with her.
他…
Did he...
有问起我吗?  盖尤斯?
Ask about me? Gaius?
他想知道你过的好不好
He wanted to know if you were well.
他想让你知道他有多么的想你
He wanted you to know that he misses you.
爱你
Loves you.
因为不能来亲自告诉你
Because he can't be here to tell you,
他让我把这个带给你
he gave me this, to give to you.
他冒死用这个
He uses that, at the risk of grave reprisal,
来表达他的感情
to express his feelings,
使他的世界变得有序可辨
to put his world into some kind of recognizable order.
使他的心声能被听见
To be heard.
他藏着它  因为他知道他再也得不到另一支了
He's kept it hidden because he knows he will not get another.
他希望你拥有它
He wants you to have it
因为没有你  一切都没有意义
because without you it has no meaning.
他希望你拥有它 因为他会不惜一切代价
He wants you to have it because he would do anything,
与你重聚
anything, to be with you again.
真是遗憾  不是吗?
Well, that's a shame, isn't it?
因为他们绝不会让我留着它
Since they'll never let me keep it.
你知道  你时日无多  又被人掌控
You understand that your days are owned and tallied by these people.
那些人正在外面看着我们
The ones out there, watching us.
我想你知道你最终的结局是什么
I think you realize what's likely to become of you.
即使他们付十倍于我替波塔尔辩护的钱  我也帮不了你
I couldn't help you if they paid me 10 times what they offered me for Baltar.
你不会被审判
You won't get a trial.
就算是不公平的审判也得不到 所以
Not even a bad one. So...
我不得不问你
I have to ask you.
爱情给你的伤害和我受到的一样深吗?
Does your love hurt as much as mine?
是的
Yes.
感觉好像天要塌了
I feel like part of our world just fell down.
嘿  伙计们
Hey, guys.
当然  长官
Yes, sir. Yes, sir.
为什么鼓励他继续写作 然后又拿走他的笔?
Why encourage the man to write, and then take his pen?
如果外界知道他被禁言了 他会得到更多的同情
He'll curry more sympathy when we get the word out that he's been silenced.
暴政  压制言论自由  很有煽动性
Tyranny. Gag orders. Very sexy.
是啊  好吧
Okay, all right.
因此你就偷了他的笔  然后对他撒谎  接着又对6号撒谎
So you steal his pen, then you lie to him, then you lie to the Six.
时代的恐惧
The horror of the age.
巨大的丑闻 伪善的外衣
The great, ugly material. The cloak of deceit.
真相
The truth.
嗯
Hmm.
有点夸张了
Kind of overrated, I guess.
知道嘛  当我9岁的时候  也许10岁
You know, when I was 9, maybe 10,
我爷爷...
my grandfather,
他招手让我过去
he would wave me over.
而且他每次都这样
And he'd do this all the time.
然后他说
And then he'd say,
"李  做个乖孩子"
"Lee, be a good boy.
"但不要太乖了"
"Just don't be too good. "
每人都有邪恶的一面
Everybody has demons.
他们  波塔尔  你  我
Them, Baltar, you, me.
甚至机器
Even the machines.
法律只是驱除邪恶的一种方式
The law is just a way of exorcising them.
你老爸的老爸就是这么告诉我的
That's what your father's father taught me.
你知道我为什么恨他么?
You want to know why I hated him?
因为他是对的
Because he was right.
你憎恶他  是因为他是正确的
So, you hated him because he was right,
而我憎恶法律  是因为它是错误的
and I hated the law, because it was wrong.
因为法律使得他...
Because of what...
我是说  法律使得他
Of what it put him through.
保护了最坏的人
I mean, he defended the worst of the worst.
我记得我读过他的阅历
I remember reading about him.
暴力
The outrage.
帮暴力杀人犯开脱罪行 我不理解的是
Helping murderers go free. What I don't understand is
他为什么要把自己搅和到那些污七八糟的事情里去
why he put himself through all that abuse.
你认为他做的事情都毫无意义?
You think he gave a flying frak?
约・阿达玛很在乎一件事
Joe Adama cared about one thing,
去了解人们为什么要这么做
understanding why people do what they do.
为什么我们要欺骗朋友
Why we cheat our friends,
为什么我们要勾结敌人 为什么我们要打仗
why we reward our enemies, why we go to war.
为毫无胜算的事情浪费光阴
Sacrificing our lives for lost causes.
为什么我们希望制造机器
Why we build machines in the hope
来纠正我们的瑕疵与缺陷  我们为什么会宽恕
of correcting our flaws and our shortcomings, why we forgive.
会违背逻辑规律和自然法则
Defying logic and the laws of nature
仅仅因为那小小的愚蠢的同情心
with one stupid, little act of compassion.
我们有缺陷  我们所有人
We're flawed. All of us.
我想知道为什么
I wanted to know why.
所以我做了…
So, I did
他做过的事
what he did.
我一生都与堕落…
I spend my life with the fallen.
和败坏为伍
The corrupt, the damaged.
再看看你
Look at you.
你那么迫不及待和我一起跳入猛禽机
You were so ready to get on that Raptor with me.
做个坏孩子  屡教不改的小坏蛋
Be the bad boy, the prodigal son.
不  我只是在执行任务  保护你
No. I was just doing my job protecting you.
那你为什么要插手我的事?
What are you doing in my business?
"突然我被一堆矛盾思想禁锢了"
Suddenly I'm handcuffed to a serial contrarian.
不  我没有
No, I am not...
哦  是的
Okay, okay.
我的问题很明了啦
My bed is made.
我建议你好好想想你自己的
I suggest you toil on your own.
那么  如果盘问结束了的话
Now, if this cross-examination is over,
我想休息了
I'd like to take a crap.
罗默  你讲的那个女孩的故事  那个你爱过
Romo, that story you told about the girl, the woman that you loved,
又尝试忘记的女人… 是真的吗?
getting over her, is it true?
嘿  那是真的吗?
Hey, was it true?
是
Yes.
给他的  来自殖民地1号的文件
For him. Files from Colonial One.
终于… 我还以为要等审判结束了才能拿到呢
Finally. I thought I'd get all these after the trial was over.
等等
Hold it.
先放地板上
Put that on the floor, now.
哦  妈的
For frak's sake.
我看到凯利用X光照过了 都是些文件
I was there when Kelly X-rayed them. It's papers.
给你
There you go.
没问题吧?
Good?
是的
Yeah.
不!
No!
你有五分钟  少校
You've got five minutes, Major.
谢谢
Thank you.
在猎犬嗅到之前 打开
Before the hounds got to it. Open it.
总统的眼镜
The President's glasses.
她不戴这个更好看些
She looks better without them.
没那么严肃了
Less serious.
法庭上气氛太严肃了
Serious catches on in the courtroom.
你父亲的
Your father's.
什么时候?
When?
在甲板上
From the deck.
就是你们在猛禽机底下发现炸弹以后
Right after you found the bomb underneath the Raptor.
嘿...猫咪...猫咪
Here, kitty, kitty.
用根线穿着
It was hanging by a thread.
它锈地好快
They tarnish so fast.
在我摘掉它时就是如此
Was like that when I plucked it.
其他每个人的  泰的
Everybody else, Tigh, the others,
你的 都闪闪发光
you, all shiny.
他身上战士的气息太重了
The soldier in him has had enough for a while.
他会很乐意坐在那个法庭上展示他的火力
He'll be glad to sit in that courtroom and fire his missiles there.
走廊尽头
Ms. Prosecuting Attorney.
那个控方律师小姐的
Down the hall.
别想歪了
It's not what you think.
我的想法还是比较纯洁的
It was appropriated with the noblest of intentions.
看看鞋底
See the soles?
看看这鞋底磨的
See how the soles are worn?
她走路拖步子
She drags her feet.
你理解上去了
You're catching on.
其他的呢?  这些都是什么?
And the rest? What's all this?
我邪恶的一面
My demons.
我"借"了些东西
I borrow things.
我的父母在我9岁时失踪了
My parents disappeared when I was 9 years old.
他们被绑架了
They were kidnapped.
被撕票了
Murdered for...
因为身上的钱不够
For the money they had on them, which wasn't enough.
我去和一个叔叔生活
I went to live with an uncle.
逃走之前从他那里偷了这些
Stole from him until I could run away.
那么你从我这拿了什么?
So, what did you take from me?
我在想你带在身上的照片
I was thinking the photograph that you carry.
那个飞行员女孩
That girl. The pilot.
你带在身边的那张
The one you carry on you.
但你被偷走的已经够多的了
But you've had enough stolen from you already.
不知何故...我想我会设法把这个还给她的
I'll try and get these back to her somehow.
后面还有一个口袋
The other pocket, at the back.
守卫从她那里拿走
The guards took it from her.
我又从他们那儿"借"走了
I borrowed it from them.
我们仍有个快要审理的案子
I still have a case pending.
如果你想要帮忙
If you want to help,
如果你敢帮这个忙
if you dare to help,
把这个还给我的当事人
get this to my client.
案子?
A case?
我有职业操守
I have a calling,
在我耳边不断地提醒我
so the ringing in my ears tells me.
好吧  你最好解释一下这个
Okay, you better explain this.
我甚至不知道这是什么
Don't even know what it is.
我知道  你从哪儿拿来的?
Well, I do. Where did you get it?
那个把你当小学生一样教训的人
The one that scolded you like a schoolboy,
妈的  用用你的脑子  他的名字? 严肃先生
frakking with your head. What's his name? Mr. Serious.
凯利
Kelly.
凯...凯利?
Kelly?
是的
Yeah.
你在那架猛禽机上 我是绝对不会上雅典娜升空的
I never would have let Athena go airborne with you in the Raptor.
你知道  我会阻止的
I would have stopped it. You know that.
是  我知道
Yeah, I know that.
你最好把我关起来
You better lock me up.
我不想要什么审判 我不会停止的
And I don't want any trial. I won't stop.
我会继续尝试
I will keep trying.
我会坚持不懈  我会的
I'll keep at it, I will.
我做了自己的工作  长官
I did my job, sir,
我已经干了两年
and I have done my job for two years now.
每天我送人们去战场
Every day, I sent people out to fight,
然后帮他们收尸
I cleared them all to die.
那么多人
So many people.
我不想再这样子下去了
I just got tired of living with that.
你问问那个人  如果要选
You ask that man, if he had to choose
是为人类死  还是为赛昂死?
between giving his life up for a Cylon or a human,
你猜他会怎么说
what do you think he'd say?
我必须做点什么
I had to do something.
副长  恢复阿达玛少校…
XO, reinstate Major Adama
的空军飞行队长身份
as Commander of the Air Group.
立即生效
Effective immediately.
很高兴你回来了
It's good to have you back.
谢谢
Thank you.
很抱歉 我错了
I'm sorry. I guess I was wrong.
我把事情搞得更糟糕了   不
I made it worse. No.
不 你知道你应该在你的战机里
No, you should be in your bird.
我想我该和拉姆金在一起
I think I should be with Lampkin.
既然我们知道了是凯利干的
Well, now that we know that it was Kelly,
我们就可以稍微放松一下安全措施了
we can ease up a little bit on security.
就拉姆金的身体状况来看 我想他需要人帮他准备审判
In his condition, I think Lampkin needs help preparing the trial,
陈述案情
presenting his case.
总统还有些其他候选人 她在考虑
The President has a few possibilities. She's looking.
爸  为什么不是我?
Dad, why not me?
我熟悉案子  读过文件
I'm close to the case, I've read the documents.
我了解拉姆金的策略
I understand Lampkin's strategy.
事情都在我们控制之中
We have things under control.
拉姆金会得到帮助的
Lampkin will have help.
我想做这个
I wanna do this.
你是空军飞行队长
You're a CAG.
你不是律师 差的远了
You're not a lawyer. Far from it.
难道你就是法官了?
What? And you're a judge?
不是  但就像其他四个被挑选出来的人
No. But like the four other men picked,
我有能力采纳证据
I'm capable of listening to the evidence
作出合理的判断
and making an ethical decision.
我有能力辅助拉姆金
And I'm capable of helping Lampkin.
别说了
Forget it.
我要你当好空军飞行队长
I need you as CAG.
那你为什么给我这些书?
Why did you give me those books? Huh?
我是说  你给了我你父亲的法律书
I mean, you gave me your father's law books.
我犯了个错误
I made a mistake.
为什么  为什么是个错误?
Why? Why is it a mistake?
你怕我变成他那样?
Are you afraid that I'll be like him?
你是飞行员
You're a pilot.
因为扎克和卡拉都死了
And with Zak gone and Kara gone, you need someone
你需要有人把旗帜扛起来  是吗?
to carry the flag. Is that it?
你是飞行员并且你是我儿子
You're a pilot and you're my son.
我不想看到你坐在法庭的另一边
I will not look across that court and see you sitting on the other side.
看到我?  还是看到其他人?
See me? Or see someone else?
回去报到吧
Report for duty.
这是命令吗?
Is that an order?
你跑题太远了
You're in way over your head.
回去报到
Report for duty.
这是命令吗?!
Is that an order?
我不会再对你下命令了
I'm through giving you orders.
把阿波罗开除出甲板 通知西洛他还是空军飞行队长
Remove Apollo from the board. Inform Helo he's to remain at CAG.
我儿子还有更重要的事要照料
My son has more important things to tend to.
嘿  腿怎么样了?
Hey, how's the leg?
你是说我中的大奖吗?
You mean my lucky break?
给了我个不来这儿的理由
Gave me a reason not to come up here.
迟早
Sooner or later,
你会用完借口的
you run out of excuses.
很难就这样让她走了...
It's hard to let her go.
李
Lee...
回头见
I'll see you around.
没有更伟大的同盟 没有更强大的力量
LAMPKIN: "There's no greater ally, no force more powerful,
没有更顽固的敌人
"no enemy more resolved,
比得上一个愿意走出父亲阴影的儿子
"than a son who chooses to step from his father's shadow.
罗默・拉姆金
"Romo Lampkin. "